utne.com 2019-07-07

# Utne Magazine - Privacy Policy

Ogden Publications, Inc. (collectively referred to in this Privacy Statement as "we," "us," or "Ogden Publications, Inc.") recognize the importance of protecting the privacy of all information provided by users of our websites, subscribers to our magazines, registrants for our events, recipients of our email newsletters and all of our customers. We created this policy with a fundamental respect for our users’ right to privacy and to guide our relationships with our users. This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for all products and services owned by Ogden Publications, Inc. A current list of our publications, websites, and products can be found at <http://www.ogdenpubs.com/>.

## INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE

Ogden Publications, Inc. collects information from our website users, magazine subscribers, email subscribers and customers. Below, we will describe the type of information we collect and how we use it to provide better services to our customers.

### Website

When you visit our website we may automatically collect non-personally identifiable information, such as online behavior and information about your computer, mobile or other device. The information collected may include, without limitation, the make, model, settings, specifications (e.g., CPU speed, connection speed, browser type, operating system, device identifier) and geographic location of you and/or your computer, mobile or other device, as well as date/time stamp, IP address, pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, the site(s), application(s), destination(s), and/or service(s) you arrived from, and other clickstream data. We use this information to monitor and improve our websites and Services.

This information is collected through a third party service, Google Analytics.

We also use SiteCore Experience Marketing to track online behavior and serve content specific to your website usage. None of the information they collect personally identifies you to us. This is done through the use of a cookie, you can find out more information about our cookie usage below.

### Magazine Subscription

When you subscribe to one of our publications, we may ask you to provide your name, mailing address, email address, phone number and credit card or other payment information. This information is collected so that we can fulfill your subscription, send you invoices, and contact you about your subscription. Once you become a subscriber we may store your subscription information, including its start date, renewal date, pricing, publication, and any customer service contacts you may have with us.

### Store Purchase

When you purchase products offered through one of our websites or publications, we may ask you to provide your name, mailing address, email address, phone number, and credit card or other payment information. We also keep a history of your purchases. We use this information to fulfill your purchase, to better assist you when you visit or contact us in the future, and improve our product offerings.

### Payment Information

For our services that require payment (such as certain events, products and subscriptions), we also collect credit card information (such as account name, number, expiration date, and verification code), which is used for billing purposes only. We utilize a service, Cybersource, to assist with payment management. For more information on how they handle personal data please visit their [privacy policy](https://www.cybersource.com/privacy/).

### Online Registration

Registration may be required to participate in certain website features, such as commenting. When you register, you may be asked for personal information such as your name, email address, and a user name and password that you select. We collect this information to identify who you are, to provide you with access to the service you requested, and communicate forgotten password notifications.

Note that all personal information sent or posted via your commenting appears on our site and becomes public information for which we are not responsible.

### Newsletter

When you sign-up for our newsletters, we may ask you to provide your name, email address, demographic information, hobbies, and interests. We use this information to provide the requested services as well as provide relevant special offers. We use demographic information about our audience to improve our service, for marketing purposes and/or industry reporting purposes.

We use a third-party provider, WhatCounts, to deliver our email messages. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies to help us monitor and improve our newsletter. For more information, please see [WhatCounts privacy policy](https://www.whatcounts.com/privacy-policy/).

You can opt-out of our email messages at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions located near the bottom of each message. If you have received an email in error, or would like to submit a complaint regarding an email message you received, please contact our [Customer Care Department](http://www.ogdenpubs.com/customer-service.aspx) or call 800-678-5779.

### Promotions

When you enter a contest, sweepstakes or giveaway (“promotion”) we may ask you to provide your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, demographic information, and interests. We use the information collected to administer your participation in the promotion and to notify the winners and award prizes. Name, city and state will also be listed on our promotion winner’s page, this is necessary to comply with promotion laws.

We may offer promotions that are sponsored or co-sponsored or presented with identified third parties. The third parties will be identified on the promotion entry form. By participating in such promotions the information you voluntarily submit may be provided to both Ogden Publications, Inc. and the third parties identified on the form. Ogden Publications has no control over the third parties’ use of this information. Participation in these promotions is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether to disclose requested information.

### Surveys

When you participate in a survey or poll we may ask you to provide your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, demographic information, and/or interests. We use this information for market research, audience analysis and to improve our Services. We use a third-party provider, Survey Monkey, to conduct our surveys and polls. For more information, please see [Survey Monkey’s privacy policy](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/).

We may also share survey information with advertisers and marketing partners in an aggregated, non-personally identifiable form. Personal information will only be provided to third parties after ensuring that depending on the circumstances you have either consented or not objected.

### Email this Article

If you elect to use our referral service for informing a friend about our articles, sites and services, we may ask for the friend's name and email address. Ogden Publications, Inc. will store and use this information to send the friend an invitation. This information may also be used to provide the friend information about our company and related products and services. The friend may contact us as specified in the subsequent message to request that no further communications be sent.

### Communications with Us

We have features where users can submit information to us (such as our comment/feedback forms). Letters to the editor and similar submissions may be made public. Requests for service, support or information may be forwarded as needed to best respond to a specific request. We may retain emails and other information sent to us for our internal administrative purposes, and to help us to serve customers better.

### Communications from Us

In order to best serve our customers, we may send updates that contain important information about our sites and services. For example, we may send new members a welcome message, confirmations on purchases or verification of password and username for our password-protected sites. We may also communicate with a user to provide requested services and for account-related issues via email, phone or regular mail.

We offer our users the option to receive information about our company and related products, services and special deals. Users can choose not to receive these communications, as set forth in our Permission section below.

## COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGY

Our websites have features that automatically collect information from users, to deliver content specific to users' interests and to honor their preferences. This information assists us in creating sites that will serve the needs of our users.

We use "cookies," a piece of data stored on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. The use of cookies and pixels enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our sites.

Further, beacons are used in email messages to measure the effectiveness of our messaging and how visitors use our website.

### Disabling Cookies

You can set your browser to accept or reject most cookies, or to notify you when a cookie is set. This can be done by visiting the relevant support page for your browser.

Alternatively, you can opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting [DAA opt-out page](http://www.aboutads.info/) and/or [NAI consumer opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

### Types of Cookies We Use

1. **Necessary** Cookies: These cookies are essential, as they enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as accessing logged in or secure areas. The website cannot function properly without them.

2. **Statistics** : These cookies help website owners to understand how visitors interact with websites by collecting and reporting information anonymously.

3. **Marketing** Cookies: Marketing cookies are used to track visitors across websites. The intention is to display content and promotions that are relevant and engaging for the individual user and thereby more valuable for publishers and third party advertisers.

**Cookie**

| 

**Type**

| 

**Purpose**  
  
---|---|---  
  
ASP.NET_SessionId

| 

Necessary

| 

This is a cookie used by ASP.NET to store a unique identifier for your session.  
  
Google Doubleclick, AdSense and AdWords

| 

Marketing

| 

Used for ad serving and targeting. [View Google’s privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/).  
  
Google Analytics

| 

Statistics/Marketing

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our website. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the website. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the website, where visitors have come to the website from and the pages they visited. [View Google’s privacy policy](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245).  
  
Mircosoft Bing ads

| 

Marketing

| 

We use the pixel to track website traffic, create audiences to retarget on Bing Ads, or track conversions from our Bing ads. [View Bing Ads privacy policy](https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/microsoft-bing-ads-privacy-policy).  
  
Facebook Pixel

| 

Marketing

| 

We use the pixel to track website traffic, create audiences to retarget on Facebook, or track conversions from our Facebook ads. [View Facebook’s cookie policy.](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/)  
  
YouTube

| 

Marketing

| 

We use YouTube to store and show video content. These cookies are set by YouTube to track usage of its services. [View Google’s privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/).  
  
SiteCore Analytics

| 

Marketing

| 

This cookie is used to track user behavior on the website and serve relevant content and ads to that user.  
  
Optinmonster

| 

Necessary

| 

We have a pop up appearing on the website for newsletter and subscription promotion, if you engage with it or dismiss it the cookie will prevent you from seeing the pop up again during the duration of your visit. [View optinmonster’s privacy policy. ](https://optinmonster.com/privacy/)  
  
Adventive

| 

Marketing

| 

Collects anonymous statistical data to understand how online ads are served and interacted with. [View adventive’s privacy policy](https://www.adventive.com/privacy-policy/).  
  
### Third-party Cookies Linked to Social Networks

If you have previously logged into a social network, such as Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest or LinkedIn, and remain logged in your browser will send the social network information from the cookie they dropped when you visit websites that offer “Like” and/or “Share” buttons. This will occur even if you do not use these buttons. We have no control over the processes used by social networks and therefore ask you to consult the privacy policy on their websites.

## WITH WHOM YOUR INFORMATION IS SHARED

On occasion, we may provide targeted lists of names and offline and online contact information for marketing purposes to third parties, subject to our Permission policies. We give users the option of not having their name or contact information disclosed to third parties, as set forth in the Permission section.

Other than as set forth above, we do not share personally identifiable information with other companies, apart from those acting as our agents in providing our product(s)/service(s), and which agree to use it only for that purpose and to keep the information secure and confidential. Also, our parent, subsidiary and affiliate companies, entities into which our company may be merged, or entities to which any of our assets, products, sites or operations may be transferred, will be able to use personal information. In the event your information is shared due to one of these reasons we will notify you. We will also disclose information we maintain when required to do so by law, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena or other legal obligation, in response to a law enforcement agency's request, or in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights or property. Users should also be aware that courts of equity, such as U.S. Bankruptcy Courts, might have the authority under certain circumstances to permit personal information to be shared or transferred to third parties without permission.

We may share aggregate information, which is not personally identifiable, with others. This information may include usage and demographic data, but it will not include personal information.

## CORRECTING, UPDATING, AND ACCESSING PERSONAL INFORMATION

We will take reasonable steps to accurately record the personal information that you provide to us and any subsequent updates. You are entitled to view, amend, or delete the personal information that we hold. To do this please contact our [Customer Care Department](http://www.ogdenpubs.com/customer-service.aspx) or call 800-678-5779.

You may request that we delete personal information about you that is inaccurate, incomplete, or irrelevant for legitimate purposes, or are being processed in a way which infringes any applicable legal requirements, by contacting our [Customer Care Department](http://www.ogdenpubs.com/customer-service.aspx) or call 800-678-5779. At our election, instead of deleting such information, we may retain it with your comment or correction noted in our records. By contacting us, you may also object to our further use of your personal information if you have compelling legitimate grounds (this may involve closing your account). We may ask you to verify your identity and to provide other details before we are able to provide you with any information, correct any inaccuracies, or delete any information. Your right to review, update, correct, and delete your personal information may be limited, subject to the law or your jurisdiction: (i) if your requests are abusive or unreasonably excessive, (ii) where the rights or safety of another person or persons would be encroached upon, or (iii) if the information or material you request relates to existing or anticipated legal proceedings between you and us, or providing access to you would prejudice negotiations between us or an investigation of possible unlawful activity. Upon request of deletion we will take action and provide you information on the action taken within 30 days.

### PERMISSION

Our users are given the opportunity to choose whether to receive information not directly related to the registered services from our affiliates and us. Users also have the opportunity to choose whether to have personal information shared with third parties for marketing purposes. If you do not wish to have your personally identifiable information shared with third parties, contact our [Customer Care Department](http://www.ogdenpubs.com/customer-service.aspx) or call 800-678-5779. If you do not wish to receive future commercial messages from us, simply follow the unsubscribe instructions contained within the message you receive. Please note that we will endeavor to implement requests within a reasonable time, although for a time users may continue to receive mailings, etc., transmitted based on information released prior to the implementation of the request. Users will continue to receive information directly related to their registered services, so they always are kept informed.

Please note, however, that even if you "opt out" as described above, we will not be able to remove Personally Identifiable Information about you from the databases of affiliates or third parties with which we have already shared your Personally Identifiable Information. If you wish to stop receiving marketing messages from such affiliates or third parties, please contact them directly or utilize the opt-out mechanisms set forth in their respective privacy policies or marketing messages.

If you prefer not to receive traditional mail or other off-line promotions from this or any other Ogden Publications property or any companies not owned by Ogden Publications please call 800-678- 5779 or contact our [Customer Care Department](http://www.ogdenpubs.com/customer-service.aspx).

If you prefer not to receive email marketing from this or any other Ogden Publications property or any companies not owned by Ogden Publications, please contact our [Customer Care Department](http://www.ogdenpubs.com/customer-service.aspx) or call 800-678-5779.

Ogden Publications' sites will not use or transfer personally identifiable information provided to us in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you with an opportunity to opt out of these unrelated uses.

### NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA CUSTOMERS – YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

Under California’s “Shine the Light” law, California residents may opt out of allowing us to: (A) share Personally Identifiable Information with Ogden Publications affiliates for their direct marketing purposes; and (B) share Personally Identifiable Information with third party companies for their marketing purposes. You may indicate your preferences to opt out of any combination of the choices above by contacting our [Customer Care Department](http://www.ogdenpubs.com/customer-service.aspx) or call 800-678-5779. Please specify in your email from which choice you are opting out.

### CHILDREN’S ONLINE PRIVACY PROTECTION ACT COMPLIANCE

Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older. We do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under 13 years of age. If we determine upon collection that a user is under this age, we will not use or maintain his/her personal Information without the parent/guardian’s consent.

### SECURITY

We use reasonable precautions to protect our users' personal information and to store it securely. Sensitive information that is transmitted to us online (such as a credit card number) is 128-bit encrypted and is transmitted to us securely. In addition, access to all of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted. Only employees who need the information (for example, a billing clerk or a customer service representative) to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. Finally, the servers on which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

### PURCHASING RESTRICTIONS

Ogden Publications, Inc. does not sell products for purchase by children. If you are under 18, you may use our website only with the involvement of a parent or guardian.

### SAFE SHOPPING GUARANTEE

Under the Fair Credit Billing Act, a credit card issuer cannot make you liable for charges in excess of $50.00 that result from the unauthorized use of your credit card. There are similar federal laws that relate to debit cards. Exceptions do apply, and you will have to comply with rules of your credit card or debit card issuer, so please contact your card issuer for further details.

If through no fault of your own, a credit card or debit card issuer assesses you a fee because of the unauthorized use of your credit card or debit card on our site, Ogden Publications, Inc. will reimburse you for such amount up to $50.00. Please contact our [Customer Care Department](http://www.ogdenpubs.com/customer-service.aspx) or call 800-678-5779 for details.

### LINKS

Our websites contain links to other sites. Ogden Publications, Inc. is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each website to which we may link that may collect personally identifiable information.

### NOTIFICATION AND CHANGES

If we change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so our users are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under which circumstances, if any, we disclose it. Users should check this policy frequently to keep abreast of any changes.

For questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or any dealings with Ogden Publications, Inc, contact us at:

Corporate Communications  
Ogden Publications, Inc.  
1503 SW 42nd Street  
Topeka, KS 66609  
785-274-4300 or 800-678-5779

Updated May 24, 2018
